

DETAILS

Belarus, Vitebsk
 Open for relocation, Remote job

github.com/paulo81818

in linkedin.com/in/pavelliaoshka

🎦 pavelliaoshka818@gmail.com

+375295990701

HARD SKILLS

Data operation:

Microsoft Excel/ Google Sheets

Google Bigquery

Rstudio

Google Analytics/ Ads

Yandex Metrica/ Direct

Programming languages:

SQL, Python(Pandas, NumPy, Mathplotlib), R(Tidyverse)

Data visualization:

MS Excel / Power Point Power BI / Tableau

Languages:

English - C1

German - B2

Belorussian - Native

Russian - C2

SOFT SKILLS

Analytical thinking

Leadership experience

Problem - solving skills

Attention to detail

Ability to learn fast

Teamwork

Flexibility

EDUCATION

Belorussian State University Marketing and Logistics 2013 - 2017

COURSES

Google data analytics Certification IBM Data analysis with Python Business Analysis LinkedIn

PAVEL LIAOSHKA

ABOUT ME

During my life, I have worked in different areas, and it is always very interesting for me to find something new, study, and improve myself.

Analyzing different types of data has always been the most exciting part of my career path, from web-marketing and search behavior data to sales and financial data analysis. It's very impressive: discover interesting insights, patterns that can be beneficial, represent them like a story using appealing data visualizations, and use that to help people solve their problems.

I like to travel and communicate with people from different countries, so one of my old hobbies is learning English and German.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Financial | Digital Marketing Analytics Specialist

"Amand" | December 2020 - July 2022

Company selling wide range of construction materials online and offline.

- Analysis of financial and digital marketing data in Excel, Bigquery, and Rstudio (using R and Python).
- Identifying relationships in product sales, patterns in customer behavior.
 Mathematical regression analysis with Python, discover correlations in the sales of certain types of materials.
- Identifying the most profitable sales leaders and product groups.
 Classifying products by sales volume, profit, customer type, and another criterion
- Assessing the effectiveness of working with various suppliers. Determine
 which supplier's products to promote more heavily, balancing customer
 preferences and the benefits of working with a particular supplier. Profit
 had increased by an average of 4%.
- Making appropriate changes in advertising campaigns. It helped to reduce web marketing costs by about 25%, increase online sales by about 18% (compared to the previous month before implementation), and save the results further.
- identifying optimal stock structure: low-liquid goods were reduced, which made room for highly liquid goods.
- Organization of additional data collection through surveys and a discount program. Merging gathered data with internal sales data Processing, cleaning data in Spreadsheets, SQL.
- Prediction of consumer demand for a certain period of time, using internal sales data for the last few years. Make recommendations for stock optimization, digital marketing investments.
- Drawing up monthly/annual reports, dashboards, forecasts, and data visualizations using MS Excel, Power BI, and Power Point.

Digital Marketing/Analytics Specialist

Freelance | February 2017 — October 2021

- Product analysis: investigating a company's product or service, including its online presence, website, market analysis, and competitive offers.
- Digital Marketing analysis of existing advertising companies. Identifying the needs of potential customers and analyzing their search behavior in Google Analytics and other analytical systems.
- Creating User Acquisition strategy.
- Running advertising campaigns in Google and another search engines.
- Analysis of advertising campaign statistics. Find a way for improvement.
- A/B testing of ads. Analyzing statistics and identifying the most effective.
- Changing advertising campaigns and content on websites. Increasing the relevance of ads in search and content on the site to search queries can save up to 50% of the advertising budget while increasing CTR and ROI and decreasing CAC (customer acquisition cost).
- Producing reports (Excel, PowerPoint) that include data on the effectiveness of advertisements, search keywords, conversions, CTR, ROI, CAC and other metrics. Record changes in logs.

Logistics, Cargo transportation

Business Owner | March 2016 - February 2020

- Cargo transportation and storage organization using various modes of transportation.
- Analyzing web-marketing data using Google Analytics and Yandex.Metrica. Editing ads, making appropriate changes to increase effectiveness.
- Website maintenance, working with advertising companies on Google.Ads and Yandex.direct.
- Leading a four-person team. Working with customers, financial and tax document management using MS Excel, Word.